area of a circle is pi r squared why is
that how did they figure this out
you can split the circle up into pieces
i split it up into ten pieces here
as we separate them we start to rotate
them like this and line them up and if
we bring them together
i just took all these pieces of the
circle and turned it into a
parallelogram now it's true these are
little curves
the more slices you cut it into the
straighter those curves will be and if
you cut it into an infinite number of
slices
all those curves will go into a straight
line so essentially the circle is the
same thing as this parallelogram the
area of a parallelogram is base times
height so what is the base
and what is the height if we pull our
parallelogram apart you'll notice that
this base
is half of the circumference and
circumference is 2 pi r
so half of the circumference would be pi
r next let's talk about the height if we
pull out one of the slices you'll notice
that the height
is the same thing as the radius of the
circle so we have a base of pi
r and a height of r therefore the area
of this parallelogram
is pi r squared area of a circle is pi r
squared